all right welcome everybody in this
tutorial we're going to talk about how
to make local variables inside of your
functions to do that let's consider what
the stack looks like because we need to
start to be able to make local variables
because if you were to define a variable
inside of your data section or your BSS
section and those variables not going to
be local they're going to be effectively
global to all of your functions inside
your text section and the difference
between global and local variables is
that they can be global variables can be
seen
throughout the whole program whereas
local variables are seen with respect to
that particular function at your end
so in this case we're going to be
declaring a local variable inside of
main and how we do that is by utilizing
the stack and if you recall real briefly
the stack looks like this here whenever
you enter a new function the base
counter is saved like right here and
then next we create a new base pointer
all right so we saved the base pointer
we create a new one and we reserve space
so to create a local variable we reserve
space on the stack for where our local
variables will reside and so without
further ado let's get to actually
creating one so effectively by reserving
space we've already created our local
variables and if you see you again the
stack looks like this one it's called
the return address is pushed with an
offset of 4 from the base puncher
so this is plus 4 plus another 4 which 8
plus another 4 which is 12 and here to
look to make our to utilize the local
variables we just need to do an offset
of negative 4 so minus 4 and minus
another 4 to get 8 for the second one
and so on and so on and so on
all right so we've declared space for
variable let's assign um let's assign
our first variable some value so to do
that we say move D word based punter and
we make an offset of four and this is
usually whenever you see a base point
two minus four where we are always
talking about local variables as opposed
to saying EBP plus four now we're
talking about parameters that are passed
to our function in this case we're just
talking about the local variables and
we're going to click assign this local
variable the value of to 255 okay so now
we run now the place variable how do we
know to actually have the value well
let's still utilize our friend the
printf statement and let's go back and
declare a string that's going to be
allow allow us to see the value inside
of this variable that we played here so
we say message one message one will be
defined by
so there we go now we go back here and
we say push d-word the contents the
variable the value in that instead of
data address of EU t minus 4 so we push
that Val value stored in a variable we
push the value and next we push the
address of our message so now we push
the address of the message and now we
call printf so let's go ahead and
compile this see what's going on
all right and so the value is for 4095
that's because I added an extra value
right there and so now we change that
have you compiler again and run and as
you can see it is 255 like we promised
and so yeah that's how you make local
variables so real quick out to declare
another one all we have to do is say is
make another move D word of EBP minus 8
this is variable 2 and we're going to
say it's going to be 10
we compile and we run see it contains
the value tickets 5 to 16 and so yeah
that's how you create local variables
inside of your assembly function by
effectively utilizing the stack and
recognizing that the stack grows
downwards in memory so it's going to go
ahead every time you push something onto
the stack you're going down this way and
so to create a stack frame you save the
value of a base pointer so you have a
constant reference to where this is
instead of it dynamically always
changing it's going to be static right
here and so now you can make references
by going plus 4 minus 4 and minus 4 as
always you're always trying to access
local variables with respect to EBP
while plus 4 means that you're trying to
access parameters pass to your function
so yeah in the next tutorial we'll go
more in detail with the stack and use
variables to make a for loop thank you
I'll see you two next time please
remember to rate and subscribe